→ JYOTI BOSE ⊶ DATA SCIENCE AND SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

CONTACT



+91-8390904417



https://github.com/ijbo



https://www.linkedin.com/in/jyotibose-39596211/

PROFILE

Experience of 13+ years in Software Design and Development.

Data Science with 6+ years of experience.

Organize, Visualize, Understand & Presage customer data.

Connect Business with AI & Machine Learning pipelines to expand on Volume, Velocity and Variety.

Customers: COMCAST, SPRINT, ISRO, INTEL, VMWARE, DELL

DETAILED PROFILE: GitHub and Linked

SKILLS

- MACHINE LEARNING
- DEEP LEARNING
- PYTHON [PYTORCH, TF, KERAS]
- **BIGDATA** HADOOP, SPARK
- CLOUD AWS, GOOGLE, AZURE
- NLP AND COMPUTER VISION
- PLOTLY, PANDAS, SCIKIT
- PIPELINE [KAFKA, KUBERNETS, DOCKER, KIBANA]
- TELECOM BSS/OSS
- DEVOPS & SRE
- NO SQL MONGO, CASSENDRA
- o IOT

EXPERIENCE

Calsoft: 2019-Till Date

Language Modeling in NLP: Bugzilla, Jira and Service now, all the three are converted into a smart and intelligent platform, we in Calsoft have created an IP using AI and ML to reduce the ticketing resolution and assignment time.

Solar Cell Defects with CV: Intel inhouse collected images of Solar cell where in Calsoft we used machine learning to classify images into defects. This model is used to distinguish maintenance and insurance cost of the solar cells.

Data analytics tools with Plotly: I-sight is a tool we developed in house and open sourced it, to do data analytics, visualization and machine learning

Amdocs: 2009-2019

Nonnegative Learning for Data Clustering: Machine learning algorithms using matrix factorization models to better detect groups or clusters in various data sets. The algorithms can be directly applied for, e.g., Recommendation Systems and Market Segmentation.

Mobile usage to find fraud and financial health of customer. Machine Learning: Are used to analyses data and provide the answer to whether a transaction and customer was genuine or fraudulent. To create a set of rules that model customer's normal behavior and can be trained, using examples of fraud, to detect anomalies. (boosting techniques) ensemble multiple weak classifiers into one strong classifier - they were built using an ensemble of decision trees.

Telecom Projects: High/low level solution development on billing and mediation layer of BSS. Comcast new line of business where Wifi requests and IOT are first time served with the help of Amdocs Charging platform. Analyze, design and coordinate the development of software systems to form a basis for the solution of information processing problems.

CERTIFICATIONS

GOOGLE: ML and BIG DATA INTEL: ML

COURSERA: ML

COURSERA: ML pipeline

EDUCATION

B.Tech: JUIT: 2003-2007:

Electronics & Communication

Engineering, 67%

ISC: 2001 2002) St Dominic Savio

College, 64%

ICSE: (1999 2000) St Dominic Savio

College, 72%